There is a special value in Python for none or null, meaning no value, and that has the
special keyword none. If you see, if I type it in the repo, I don't get any output,
which when you think about it, kind of makes sense, right? If I try to use a variable that
I have not defined in my session at all, I will get in name error that says name
goodbye is not defined. But if I want to have a placeholder variable, I can go ahead and
say that goodbye is equal to the keyword none with a capital N, and then it's defined
within the scope of my program, even though it doesn't have a value.
Now, there are three helpful methods in the repo that you're going to end up using all
the time. So if you have a post-it note handy for things that you want to take away from
this class, I recommend writing these three down. I use them all the time, day in, day out.
And these are, we have help, type, and there.
Now the first one is going to tell us what the type of a variable is. So if I have a number
here, I can pass that into the type built in method, and it will return class in.
I can also pass in a value as well. So if you're not sure about what the type of something
is, either while you're in the repo or as your executing code, you can figure it out
this way. Let's try this with E string. What will I see when I get back, when I ask
for the type of name, which built in class? Stir. Yes, that's exactly right.
Now, now that we know the objects type, we can move on to other methods. DERS stands
for directory, which means, show me the directory of all the methods that are available
for this type. And I want to call DERS on the type, not the variable name or the value
of the variable, but on the type itself. So in this case, I can ask for the DERS of
cluster. Because remember, if I type Stir in my repo here, I'll see cluster. This is
a built in type. I don't have to define it. So when I type DERS of Stir, I will see all
of the methods that are available on strings. You can, for the most part, ignore all of
these that have the double underscores. Those are internal methods that aren't meant to
be used. And if you take a look at the other ones, you'll see some really useful ones.
Like, is alpha meaning? Does the string only contain characters and not numbers? There's
a split method for splitting a string on tokens. There's a title method for title casing
something. So that's how you can kind of very quickly see what is available on the type
that I'm working with. Now, the last one is super awesome. Because it lets you see documentation
for Python right in your repo without having to open a browser, figure out what version
you're looking for, navigate, and search. And that is help. So with help, you also want to
pass in a class. So if I type help for Stir, it's going to open this up for me, this interface.
I can press space to scroll down, or I can press Q for to quit. And that is for Linux and Mac
systems. And I'd be something different in Windows. So this is a lot of stuff. This isn't
very helpful. Instead, I find it helpful to call help on a particular method. And I can do that
by saying dot and then picking any one of these. And that just prints out the help for that
specific method. And it also shows me what arguments this method expects. So is alpha returns true
if the string is an alphabet-extring false otherwise? If you're ever not sure, like, oh, I don't
remember the name of that method or I don't remember what this does or I don't remember what
arguments this accepts. You can always reach for help. And I believe that you can call help
on values as well. Maybe not. Let's try this out. Yeah. So Dirt is, um, oh, sorry. That is not what I wanted.
I have a file named I. Yeah. So, um, for help you also want to make sure that you're passing
in the class and not, like, a variable name or a value. Make sure that you remember these three
commands and you will not find yourself too lost.